<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>I Love Symposia! (Posts about TED)</title><link>https://ilovesymposia.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://ilovesymposia.com/categories/ted.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:jni.soma@fastmail.com"&gt;Juan Nunez-Iglesias&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:11:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The electric car of the... Present?</title><link>https://ilovesymposia.com/posts/2009/07/18/the-electric-car-of-the-present/</link><dc:creator>Juan Nunez-Iglesias</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I Love Symposia!&lt;/em&gt; is going back to its roots, with a post about a TED talk!
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/shai_agassi_on_electric_cars.html"&gt;his talk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shai_Agassi"&gt;Shai Agassi&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="http://www.betterplace.com/"&gt;Better Place&lt;/a&gt; lays out his vision for cheap electric cars running on electricity from 100% renewable sources, and using technology available &lt;em&gt;today&lt;/em&gt;. If you live in Israel, Denmark, Australia or Northern California, you are first in line to try out their cars, which will be built by Renault and Nissan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ted id=512]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agassi gets around the problem of the limited range of electric cars by making the battery quickly and easily replaceable. Thus you'll stop at a &lt;span style="text-decoration:line-through;"&gt;petrol&lt;/span&gt; battery station and a robotic system will swap out the battery in less than two minutes—presto! Instant battery recharge. That's less time than it takes to fill up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With one trillion dollars set aside for the economic stimulus, it'll be disappointing if none of it goes to building battery change stations in the US. Ditto for China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're lucky enough to be in one of the pilot regions, be sure to go to the &lt;a href="http://www.betterplace.com/"&gt;Better Place&lt;/a&gt; website for more information! If not, then follow Al Gore's advice and invest in green tech. As Agassi says, this is now a &lt;em&gt;moral&lt;/em&gt; choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Just as a quick aside, I was happy to discover that Wordpress.com now allows you to embed TED talks! If you use Wordpress.com, find the announcement &lt;a href="http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2009/04/15/ted-ideas-worth-spreading/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the instructions &lt;a href="http://support.wordpress.com/videos/ted-talks/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>green technology</category><category>TED</category><guid>https://ilovesymposia.com/posts/2009/07/18/the-electric-car-of-the-present/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 11:28:54 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>